# **Blake Fromkin**

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience in the JavaScript/TypeScript ecosystem, and I'm also proficient with Go. I leverage the creative problem-solving skills I honed in my previous role as an Associate Creative Director to tackle complex engineering challenges and communicate effectively with my teammates. Most recently, I created Reverb \( \triangle \), an event-driven workflow engine that orchestrates the logic and infrastructure developers need to build complex background sequences.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Back-End**

Node.js, Express, Golang, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, Handlebars, Jest

#### Cloud

AWS, DigitalOcean, Heroku, Fly.io

#### Front-End

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, React, jQuery, HTML/CSS

## Other

Git/GitHub, GH Actions, Docker, WebSockets, Microservices, Queues, SQL, HTTP, OOP, Nginx, Postman, Bash

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Co-Creator & Software Engineer,** Reverb

2024

Reverb is an open-source, event-driven workflow engine that reliably orchestrates complex, multi-step background sequences.

- Built a robust orchestration pipeline that can accommodate a variety of workflow triggers (events, cron, webhooks) and task types (jobs, delays, conditional branching, fan-out)
- Designed a microservices architecture with independently scalable nodes for ingestion, queuing, and execution (AWS Lambda, EC2, ECS/Fargate, RDS, IAM)
- Reduced cloud deployment from 152 steps to 1 command, and automated CI/CD for containerizing and redeploying workflows (AWS CDK, GitHub Actions, Docker)
- Constructed durable PostgreSQL-backed job queues to withstand crashes and reliably execute long-running sequences (Graphile Worker, TypeScript)
- Implemented memoization with object caches to maintain workflow state across repeated TypeScript function invocations
- Designed a RESTful API with UI and CLI tools for retrieving logs, tracing events, and monitoring workflow progress (API Gateway, Lambda, MongoDB, React)
- Created a TypeScript SDK and NPM create script for developers to easily install template code, define workflows as step functions, and expose them to remote procedure calls
- Served as lead author for a comprehensive <u>technical case study</u>

# **Software Engineer,** *Open-Source Projects*

2022 - 2024

- HTTP Hoarder Real-time tool for collecting and debugging webhook requests (DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, WebSockets, MongoDB, Express, React)
- WatchIt Database-backed app to track, rate, and queue movie viewings (Express, PostgreSQL, Vanilla JS, Handlebars)
- Draft Lottery Server-side rendered (SSR) app I built for my fantasy football league's weighted draft lottery. (Express, Vanilla JS, Pug)

## **Associate Creative Director, Publicis**

2023

- Senior Copywriter (2020 2022)
- Copywriter (2019-2020)
- · Led and collaborated with cross-functional teams to generate award-winning integrated campaigns on tight deadlines
- Consistently delivered on high-profile clients' diverse business goals, integrated feedback, and led presentations to ensure success

#### **EDUCATION**

**Launch School** 2022 – 2024

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers 🗵

# Northwestern University 2012 – 2016

- Summa Cum Laude
- Television/Film & Integrated Marketing Communications